# NGUYĒN HÀI MINH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Years of Exp: 7+

0392694990

champion.minh@gmail.com

Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

# **EDUCATION**

**BACK KHOA UNIVERSITY** 

Major: Computer Science

2013 - 2017 GPA: 6.82/10

## **ABOUT ME**

The one who always tries to make everything feasible, concise, and clean.

Strong knowledge in front-end development with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and libraries such as ReactJS, Redux, React Query, Tailwind, Bootstrap, ...

Experience working with API, exposing and consuming JSON web services

Experience working with Agile/Scrum development environment with JIRA, Confluence. Experience working with source control Git (GitHub, GitLab)

Strong UI/UX design sensibility, experience with tools Figma, Invision

#### **MOST RECENT TECH STACKS:**

ReactJS, Typescript, NextJS, ASP.NET, SQL Server, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux Toolkit Query, TailwindCSS, React Query

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

TOEIC Listening & Reading 760, 2017

# **PERSONAL**

Communication • • • • •

Teamwork • • • • •

Creativity • • • • •

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**APERIA SOLUTIONS (SEPTEMBER 2023 - PRESENT)** 

- Technical stack: ReactJS, Typescript, ASP.NET, SQL Server, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux Toolkit Query
- Projects: DCH application
- + Team size: 8 (2 FE developers, 4 BE developers)
- + Responsibility: Develop new features, get requirement directly with the clients. Fix bug, enhance and improve application performance. Worked on both UI, API and DB

#### FREELANCE DEVELOPER (MARCH 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023)

- Technical stack: ReactJS, Typescript, NextJS, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux Toolkit Query, React Query, Tailwind CSS, Zustand

- Projects: E-commerce website NinjaMart, Streaming website Shahid.mbc.net, E-commerce platform zaapi.com
- + Team size: 10 (2 FE developers)
- + Responsibility: Develop feature tasks based on user story written by BA. Design common UI components. Meeting with teams to estimate tasks, provide feedbacks on design mockups

#### **APERIA SOLUTIONS (2020 - MARCH 2022)**

- Technical stack: ReactJS, Redux, Typescript, NodeJS, Bootstrap, MongoDB
- Main project: Web application for call agents to support their customer when they receive a phone call or when they make a call. The system using .NET technologies with ReactJS as the front-end
- + Team size: 24 (8 FE dev, 8 BE dev, 5 QA, 2 BA, 1 PM)
- + Client: a global fintech and payments company in US.
- + Responsibility: Develop tasks based on user story written by BA. Meeting with teams to estimate tasks, provide feedbacks on design mockups. Review code, guide junior members in technical side.
- Side project (12 months): Build common components library for projects team in the company following a design language.
- + Team size: 4 FE dev

# **WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTD.)**

**KMS TECHNOLOGY (2017 - 2020)** 

KMS - Tricentis Flood: - Technical skills: EmberJS, Typescript

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 - Responsibility: Develop a branch feature, fix bug for flood.io, a load testing platform

using EmberJS as front-end and RoR as the back-end.

- Team size: 4 FE dev, 2 BE dev, 1 BA, 1 QA, 1 SM

KMS - Internal projects: - Technical skills: ReactJS, Redux, Wordpress

Nov 2018 - Jun 2019 - Responsibility: Participate in building many react web applications for company.

- Team size: 2 FE devs

KMS - CloudFX: - Technical skills: ReactJS, Redux, Bootstrap, Jquery, Java, Docker

Apr 2018 - Nov 2018 - Client: A company based in US, providing many cloud resources management

solutions (SaaS, ITaaS)

- Responsibility: Build and develop several microservice modules An open-source

database using PHP, a React application, and couples of Java middleware

applications

- Team size: 8 dev, 2 QA, 1 BA, 1 PM

KMS - Sharecare: - Technical skills: React, Redux, AngularJS

Nov 2017 - Apr 2018 - Responsibility: Fix bug and maintain 2 websites booking appointment with doctors.

One using React and one using Angular.